截拳道讲求速度
The style of Jeet Kune Do demands speed...
准确性和力量
accuracy and power.
大师！大师
Master, Master...
外面有人来向你挑战
Someone else is here to challenge you.
He's waiting outside.
这些全是无用之辈
These fools, they'll never learn.
请用茶
Some tea for you, sir.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
请用茶
Your tea, sir.
你根本不是我对手
You're no fighter.
接住
Catch.
到你出招，动手吧
It's your move. Come on.
你敢向我挑战？
You dare to challenge me?
要不是我脚下留情，你恐怕早就没命了
You're lucky I'm a fair man,
Or else you'd be dead.
走吧
Beat it.
这些日子到处也是挑战者
Challengers are everywhere.
人人都想做天下第一
Everybody wants to be number one.
那一定有事情会发生了
Then something must be cooking.
是，有人向我挑战
Yes, I was challenged, too.
但你已经打败了他吧
But you beat him, of course.
是
Yeah.
你的意思是那是突如其来的挑战？
You mean the challenge came just out of the blue?
没错
That's right.
上星期
Last week...
我收到一个韩国功夫专家的挑战信
I received a letter of challenge
from a Korean master.
他说你和我并不是别人说的那样本事
He said people like you and
I aren't as good as our reputation.
看来有些人想我们死
Seems like quite a few people
want to see us dead.
他还说如果我到时不出现
He said if I didn't show up for the fight...
就会伤害我家人
he'd do something bad to my family.
我对这人很感兴趣，所以便决定接受挑战
I was so intrigued by his letter,
that I decided to show up.
我并不是因为怕你才来
I'm not here because of your stupid threat.
我只想看看，什么样的笨人会写那信
I just want to meet the man
who's dumb enough to write that note.
就在此一决高下吧
Come on, let's get it over with.
你记住，功夫是用来自卫的艺术
Remember, kung fu is the art of self defense.
我不会用来杀人的！
I'm not interested in killing.
让我证明你只是个功夫败类
I just want to prove how bad your kicks are.
你才是功夫败类
You must be talking about yourself.
这就是我们所谓的控制能力
That's what we call control.
你永远也不会明白的了
Something you may never understand.
老友
Now my friend, listen.
你最好祈求我们不会再见面
You'd better hope that we never meet again.
如果你敢伤害我家人，你一定会后悔的
If you dare to harm my family, you'll regret it.
因为我发誓到时候
Because I swear,
你再不会有能力打人了
you'll never be able to kick again.
我不知道这些挑战者有什么目的
I wonder what's behind all these challenges.
但我认为我们不必怕他们
But I don't think we need to fear them.
你有什么意见？
What do you think?
可能有人想致我们于死地
Someone may want us dead.
就等他们放马过来吧
Let them try.
我觉得有些不祥之兆
I think something will happen, something bad.
棍法
Use staves.
试试你们的风雷棍法
Power them like thunder.
有客人来了
A visitor.
原来是李振强，真是贵客临门
So it is you. It's Billy Lo.
阿弥陀佛
Buddha's name be praised.
大师
Abbot.
我们很久没有见面了
It's been a long time.
大师近来好吗？
Forgive me. I trust you're well.
请到后园详谈
We've much to discuss.
大师
Abbot.
刚才你一到这儿就把白鸽吓走了
The pigeons sensed your presence.
我怕
But I'm afraid
这是个不详的预兆
their swift departure is a bad omen.
你要小心
You must take care.
我会紧记的了
I shall take your advice.
振强，你要记着
Billy, remember this,
没有人是不败之躯
No one is unbeatable.
最重要的是，你弟弟向你学习
It's important that your brother learns from you.
我弟弟怎么样了
He's still making trouble?
既然你已经来了
Since you're already here
就不妨在这里住几天吧
why not stay for a few days?
你弟弟会很高兴的
Your brother would welcome it.
我明白你意思
I know what you mean.
振国这个人自小就很任性
Bobby's a rebel.
所以我今天特地来看看他
That's why I felt that I should come and see him.
一来怕他不肯专心学艺
I've determined to make sure that
he practices hard,
二来又怕他去惹是生非
work more, and I'll see that
he stays clear of trouble.
他根本不懂珍惜他的所有
Actually, he doesn't appreciate
what he has here...
能够在大师门下学习武功
The chance to learn kung fu from a master...
可算是他一生的造化
such as you.
如果我弟弟还是执迷不悟的话
But if Bobby persists in being lazy,
我一定要教训他
he must be punished.
给多些耐性吧
Be patient with him.
青年人浮躁一点是在所难免的
He's still young and impatient.
我知道振国的武功虽然是有一点根基
But I know him too well.
但这么快他已经自以为是了
So little training and he thinks he's good.
要更进一步，他就非要自强不息不可
But to become an expert, he has to study
and practice harder!
我知道他一定会听你的意见
I'm sure he will take your advice.
他是我唯一的弟弟
He's my only brother,
爹跟我都希望他学有所成
and my father and I want him to succeed
能够把我们中国的国术发扬光大
and pass on to others the benefits of kung fu.
我明白
I understand that.
我知道你非常的关心他，和他的将来
I know, too, how much you care
about him and his future.
但我希望你劝他时，语气不要太强硬
But when you talk to him, don't be too mean to him.
要友善一点，要令他明白你的意思
Be sincere with him. Make sure he understands.
还有
And remember...
你小时候也不是个到处闯祸的小孩吗？
When you were a child, you were also...
什么顽皮的事你也做过
always up to mischief.
你还不肯读书，常在街上游荡、偷东西
You didn't study hard. Instead
you wandered the streets, stealing things.
我记得
Yes, I remember that.
我当时没规矩、没分寸，亦不懂尊重别人
I had no discipline, no principles,
no respect for anybody.
你连警察也不怕呢
You weren't even afraid of the police.
你那无知的面，真的骗了很多成人
You also had that innocent look that
would fool any adult...
因为没人知道你这小鬼心想些什么
couldn't tell what that mischievous mind was up to.
你这个小贼
Hey, you little thief!
哼！你敢偷我的东西？
You're stealing my...
你还是恃强凌弱的小鬼呢
you were also a bully.
是，我是
I sure was.
你为什么这样做？
What did you do that for?
因为我不喜欢你
Because I don't like you.
我也讨厌你
And I hate you, too.
我会告诉你的父母
I'll go tell your parents.
待他们打你一顿就好了
I hope you'll get beaten.
幸好你当时不懂武功
Fortunately, you didn't know any kung fu.
但你连盲的也打
You even attacked old blind men.
身为武者，我永远不会这样做
As a martial artist I'd never do that.
我已经忘了从前的自己是那么恐怖
I'd forgotten I was such a terror.
你年纪这么小竟去袭击一个老人？
My goodness...so small,
and you dare to attack an old man!
谁管你老不老？这世界只有强者才能生存
Who cares if you're old? Only the strong survive.
我要杀了你
I'll kill you.
呀！救命呀
Help...
直到你长大，搬去和你姐一起住后
It was only later after you had grown up...
and moved in with your sister,
你才开始听话和自律
that you started listening to her pleas
for self-discipline.
妈没要我的钱
Here, Mother wouldn't take my money.
这些钱是你赌时骗回来的，她当然不要啦
Of course she wouldn't.
You got it by cheating at cards.
至少不是偷来的
At least I didn't steal it.
我知道
I know how you feel.
是我让你感到羞耻吧
You're ashamed of me.
我是家中之耻
I'm the black sheep of the family.
每个人也看不起我
Everybody despises me.
振强，我不理其他人怎说
I don't care what they say, Billy.
我和妈只在乎你对自己做了什么
Our mother and I care about
what you do to yourself.
姐，别担心，我知道怎样做了
Don't worry. I know what I have to do from now on.
妈，以前我错了
Mother, I've been wrong.
但现在我知道怎么做了
But I understand now.
我要你为我感到自豪
I'll make sure you're proud of me.
现在就轮到你弟放任了
Now it's your brother's turn.
他还年青，思想方面还没有成熟
He's still young, immature, full of his own ideas.
我肯定你和他谈了以后，他会有所改变
I'm sure he'll soon change his outlook
once you have a talk with him.
希望你说得对啦
I just hope that you're right.
你从不说错
You've never failed.
去见你的弟弟吧
Go meet your brother.
好
Right.
振国
Dear Bobby. How are you?
匆匆来访
I was hoping to see you...
未及相见
but you were out.
闻悉吾弟近来行为不甚检点，深以为憾
I gather you're not studying or training
so hard lately.
汝须知
I guess I don't have to tell you...
精武惟勤
that to become an expert in the art of kung fu
you must practice more.
惟情欲伤身，欲成大业，自当养气修身
There'll be time for girls later.
学大师之所教
Learn all that the Abbot teaches you.
今特赠拳汰一本
I'm leaving you my boxing manual.
望你潜心苦练
in the hope that you'll find it useful.
戒除旁骛
Try to concentrate.
匆负父兄期望
Don't let Father and me down.
珍重
Take care of yourself. Bye now.
兄振强留字
Your brother, Billy.
"Mysterious Death of Famous Japanese
Martial Artist Chin Ku"
死得太突然了
Died too suddenly.
你整晚也没睡
You haven't slept all night.
是
Yes, I know.
爸爸请坐
Sit down, Dad.
秦谷这么好武功
Too bad about Chin Ku.
死了实在太可惜
Kung fu expert dies so young.
是的
That's right.
你说，他会不会走火入魔呀？
Tell me. Do you think that he over-trained?
哎，你不能做什么的了
There's nothing you can do now.
不要再胡思乱想了
Don't think too much.
早点睡吧
Try to get some sleep.
爸爸你放心好了，我不会胡思乱想的
Don't worry, father. I won't let it bother me.
过两天他出殡，我想去拜祭他
I'll attend his funeral in a few days.
我想你代表我去
And I'd like you to represent me, too.
爸爸你不去呀？
You're not going?
不去了，我身体不好
No. I'm far too old to travel, my son.
路程又远
It isn't wise.
那我找振国一块儿去好不好？
Think Bobby ought to come along with me?
你还是不要去找他
No, I'd rather he didn't go.
这件事不需他知道
He shouldn't be told of this.
爸爸，为什么呢？
But why not, father?
因我不想分散他学习的精神
It's better that we shouldn't disturb the lad.
也好，那我自己去
Okay. In that case, I'll go alone.
你到那儿以后先找他的女儿
First thing to do is to look for his daughter.
怎么他有女儿？
He has a daughter?
据说这是秦谷的私生女儿
The truth is, she's his stepdaughter.
看不出他挺风流的嘛
That's a surprise. He sure kept that quiet.
这件事很少人知道
Only his friends knew the truth.
她现在在那儿？
Do you know where she lives now?
叫什么名字？
What's her name?
她的名字叫秦思美子
Her name's May
在日本的一间夜总会里面登台唱歌
I think she sings at a club in Ginza.
你就查一下吧
You'll have to make some inquiries.
欢迎
Welcome, Sir.
你来干什么？
What do you want?
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是来找你的
I'd like to talk to you.
找我？
Talk to me?
我可不认识你
I don't even know you.
我知道你不认识我
Don't let that bother you...
但我可认识你
because I know you.
你可是疯的呀
You must be crazy!
你在说什么废话？
You're talking rubbish.
我没说废话
No, I'm not.
我叫李振强
I'm Li Chun Chang.
我认识你爹
I knew your father.
是他的好朋友
We were good friends.
你爹已经死了
Your father just died.
难道你一点儿也不哀伤？
Aren't you ashamed of singing and
enjoying yourself in here?
还有那么好心情去唱歌
Don't you feel any grief at all?
我不知
I don't.
死了
So, he's dead.
又怎么样？
So what?
再哀伤他也不会回来
Being sad won't bring him back.
听你的话好像一点父女之情都没有
You seem to have very little respect
for the old man.
他从来都不照顾我
He never cared for me.
我不唱歌怎么生活？
So I sing to make a living.
话虽这么说，但他始终是你的亲生父亲
Nevertheless, you ought to respect him.
He was your father.
我妈死时他也没有来拜她
Some father! Where was he when Mother died?
过去的算了吧
Forget the past.
我当然会
You bet I will.
现在人已经死了
Nothing I can do about it now.
我想不算也不行
Just pretend it never happened.
但秦谷为什么无缘无故的死去？
I can't figure out why he died so suddenly?
他的身体一向也很好的呀
Chin Ku was a strong man, so full of life...
It's strange.
他的事我不大清楚
I don't know much about him at all.
他很久没有来看我了
We hadn't been in contact for a long time.
只是上个月来过一次
But he came to see me last month.
他很久没有来看你，那一次来一定有原因
If you lost contact for so long,
why did he suddenly come see you?
不知道
I don't know.
他只留下一盒东西，叫我好好的替他保管
But he left a box with me.
He said to keep it safe.
是什么？
What is it?
我怎会知？
I'm not sure.
我想是一盒影片
A roll of film, I think.
在那儿？
Where is the film?
能不能给我看？
Can you show it to me?
这儿
Here!
在里面
Inside this box.
我到里面看看，你在这儿等我
I'm going in. Stay here and wait for me.
我要少少时间
I need a moment.
你干什么？
What do you want?
这儿不许任何人进来
No one's allowed in here.
秦谷是我的好朋友
I'm a good friend of Chin Ku's.
我想见他最后一面
I just want to pay my last respects to him.
That's all.
什么人也不可进来
I told you, no one comes in.
聪明的话就立刻出去吧
If you're wise, leave right now!
我亲爱的儿子振国，我很遗憾地告诉你
Bobby, my son. Sadly I must tell you...
振强已经死了
that your brother, Billy, is dead.
他为了，要找出秦谷死去的原因
He was trying to find out
why his friend Chin Ku died.
为了其他人有所得着
He devoted his life to the art of kung fu.
他将生平所研究的武功心得
His own style of Jeet Kune Do...
截拳道的独特风格
recorded for the benefit of everyone...
都写在振强拳法里面
in his books and manuals.
当你收到这封信后
My son, after you've read this letter...
马上去日本找十郎
go to Japan and meet up with Sherman Lan.
查明这件事的真相，替你哥哥报仇
Find out who killed your brother. Seek revenge.
这样，他才会安息
Only then, will his soul rest in peace.
振国你好
Hey, Bobby!
十郎你好
Hi Sherman!
对不起，我迟到了
I'm sorry I'm a bit late.
我也刚到，上车再说吧
Just arrived myself. Let's go!
你哥哥生前留下的
This is all your brother left.
只是一些影片。你收起来好啦
It's a roll of film.
I think you'd better have it.
这枝镖就是杀死你哥哥的凶器
This dart is the weapon that
was used to kill your brother.
为什么他们要劫走秦谷的棺材？
Do you have any idea why
they wanted to steal Chin Ku's coffin?
那我不知道
I've no idea. It's a mystery to me.
我看这件事一定有古怪
It's all very strange.
我不明白
I don't understand.
不过总会有些原因吧
There must have been a reason.
那是什么呢？
But what?
我带你去看长老
Anyway, I'll take you to our master.
他正在等你
He's waiting for you...
十郎，我一定要报仇
Sherman, I'm going to get my revenge.
对，我们一定会帮你
Of course, we'll help you all we can.
但你要想清楚，不要意气用事
But you need to think it through carefully.
这是什么地方？
What's this place?
这就是死亡古堡
The Palace of Death.
这个外国人是谁？
Who's that foreigner?
他就是死亡堡主鲁易士
That's Lewis. Master of the palace.
这个人呢？
Who's that guy?
是他的管家
That's Lewis' valet.
那是秦谷！为什么他会在这儿？
Oh, Chin Ku...What's he doing there?
是呀，他是堡主的客人
Well, he was Lewis' guest.
他们好像是老朋友嘛
They look like great friends.
管家只有一只手
The valet's lost an arm.
但他不像残障的呀
He doesn't look handicapped, though.
他对堡主很忠心
He's very loyal to Lewis.
常常寸步不离的
Never leaves his side for a minute.
那外国人在跟秦谷学功夫？
What's Chin Ku doing...teaching Lewis kung fu?
鲁易士非常沉迷中国功夫
Seems that Lewis is interested in kung fu
据说他还好勇斗狠
for the purpose of killing. Seems to enjoy it.
简直心理变态
The man is mad!
这古堡看起来有点儿古怪
It's strange...that Palace of Death.
我一定要进去查一下
I think I'm going to check it out.
至于鲁易士
Forget Lewis.
他的功夫其实很平常
His kung fu's not that hot.
但凡是走进古堡的人
The Death Palace is a death trap.
没有一个能活着出来
No one ever leaves that place alive!
因为这古堡是个死亡陷阱，小心
So please, be very careful.
李振国在外求见
Master, there's a Bobby Lo to see you.
难道这人是李振强的弟弟？
Bobby Lo? Could he be Billy Lo's brother?
究竟这个小流氓想要什么呢
I wonder what that little punk wants with me?
叫管家请他进来吧
Tell the valet to show him in.
是
Right.
大概是为了李振强的事吧
Maybe it's about Billy's death.
你是李振国先生吗？
So you are Mr. Bobby Lo.
欢迎
Welcome.
你是李振强的弟弟，对吗？
I suppose you're Billy Lo's younger brother.
不错。听说死亡古堡是个可怕的地方
That's right. I hear the Palace of Death
really lives up to its name.
因为凡是到这里的人都不会活着走出去
They say no one leaves here alive,
我好像走进了死亡谷吧
Iike I walk into the valley of death.
不…这都是外面的人造谣生非
Not true. They're just vicious rumors.
你要知道，人就是这样
You know what people are like.
别人告诉我你跟秦谷是很要好的朋友
People tell me you were
a very good friend of Chin Ku.
是。他的武功非常的好
Yeah, his kung fu is excellent.
我很尊重他
I respect him.
我也有点妒忌他
Perhaps even jealous of him.
你说的话是什么意思？
What are you trying to suggest?
秦谷的确到我这儿来过
Chin Ku did spend some time here before,
可是他的死完全与我无关
but I have nothing to do with his death.
真的没关系？
Is that right?
这件事已经过去，我们不必再提了
Anyway, that's over, Let's forget it.
既然你有胆子到这里来
Since you had the guts to come here,
那就让我带你到处参观一下
Iet me show you around.
我想你会有兴趣的
I think you'll find it interesting.
我知道那会是个有趣的体验
I'm sure it'll be an experience.
是我的荣幸
The pleasure's all mine.
我很欣赏你的言行举止
I'm impressed with your manners.
现且看你有没有勇气
Now, let's see if you have courage.
来，你会觉得这地方很吸引的
Come on, I'm sure you'll find it fascinating.
看那边
Now, look over there.
我在那儿养了很多特别训练的孔雀
I keep a lot of specially trained peacocks.
它们都听我的指挥
They obey my every command.
孔雀也会听你的指挥？
Peacocks obeying your command?
的确是很特别
That's quite remarkable.
是的
Exactly.
它们已经过很多的训练
It takes a lot of training.
了不起，对吧？
It's quite fantastic, isn't it?
看看那边
Look at that.
是呀
Yeah.
这些全是大狮子，好怕呢
They're really big lions. God, I'm frightened!
真是四周都是狮子
There are so many of them.
这些狮子都是由非洲买回来的
They had them all imported from Africa.
是最大和最优秀的品种
I selected the biggest and best of their breed.
它们有很大的胃口
They have enormous appetites.
而且喜欢吃新鲜多汁而且生的人肉
And their favorite food is fresh,
juicy, raw human meat.
吃人不吐骨头，就是它们
They all eat a lot, bones and all.
每次我会把向我挑战而失败的人
Anyone who comes to challenge me, and then loses
都给这些畜牲当点心吃
ends up as dinner for the lions.
这些人平时都很了不起
My challengers all try to act very tough.
但一见到狮子就脚软了
But not for long.
我不觉得他们的反应有什么出奇
I'm not surprised they're scared.
希望我这一次不会变成狮子的点心就好了
I certainly hope I won't end up
as their dinner tonight.
不用担心，你不会的
Don't worry, friend. You won't.
我们在等什么？
What are we waiting for then?
走吧！走吧
Come on. Let's go. come on, ok?
狮子是万兽之王
The lion is truly King of all beasts.
是最快和最有力量的动物
They're the fastest and most powerful of all.
一个好的武术家，就应该有这种兽性
A good martial artist should have the speed
and power of a lion.
尤其是跟人搏击时
Especially when fighting his enemies,
就应该像狮子一样残忍
he should be ruthless like the lion, a killer!
那你为什么要养孔雀？
Why do you keep the peacocks?
我喜欢它们凌空飞翔的姿势
I like the way they move. So swift and so sure.
武术家不但要有狮子的勇猛
Martial artists should be fierce like a lion...
还要有孔雀的快速感
and swift like a peacock...
所以我要研究它们的动作和姿势
so I study their styles.
你的见解的确是很有趣
An interesting theory.
报告堡主
Sir,
自称西关双侠的阎氏兄弟向你挑战
two men claiming to be
the Yen brothers want to challenge you.
这两个傻人，真不知好歹
Those two stupid fools!
竟向我挑战？
There are no match for me!
孙管家，带他们去后山
All right Sun, take them to the cemetery first.
看看那些墓碑
Let them look around.
看完之后他们就可能会改变主意
May be then they'll change their minds.
是
Sir.
看，这些墓碑，就是我们堡主的成绩表
See. These are the gravestones of
my master's challengers.
你们很快就会和他们一样被埋在墓里
I'm afraid you'll be joining them very soon.
如果我是你，我就会立即离开这里
I'd leave now if I were you.
除非你想年轻早逝
unless you want to die young.
我们不会因你的话而改变主意
You can't make us change our minds.
我们就不怕死，叫他出来
We're not afraid of him! Call him out here.
都这么晚了
It's rather late.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
冈叮才有人偷袭我
Somebody has just attacked me.
有人偷袭你？
Someone attacked you?
不可能
No way.
没有人敢这样做
No one would dare to.
这个人刚刚被我打跑了
I just fought him off.
不用紧张
Take it easy.
我们明天再说吧
We'll talk tomorrow.
早
Morning!
想不到你这么早就来了
So you're an early riser, too.
请坐
Have a seat.
我会不会妨碍你吃早餐？
I hope I'm not interrupting your breakfast?
当然不会。要一起吃吗？
Of course not. Why not join me?
很好吃的
Great meal.
这是生鹿肉
This is raw venison.
和鹿血
Deer's blood.
要不要试试看？
Why not have some with me?
谢谢
No, thanks.
我不会认为这些是美味早餐
Not my idea of a nice breakfast.
昨晚的事
About last night.
你说有人偷袭你是真的吗？
Were you serious about that attack?
不用担心
Don't worry.
是我不好
It was all my fault.
我不应该那么晚了还到处乱跑
I really shouldn't have been out late anyway.
没有人可以阻你
There's nothing to stop you.
因为你是我的客人
You are my guest.
堡主，我知道你不会害我
Lewis. I know you mean me no harm...
但我觉得有人要陷害你
but I'm certain that
someone here is plotting to kill you.
真的？
Really?
有谁会做这样的事？
Who would dare to do that?
你的手下呢？你有没有怀疑过他们？
What about your staff?
Did you suspect any of them?
告诉我，你为什么会雇用这个管家？
Tell me...why did you employ your valet?
他是不是一早已断了手？
Has he always been handicapped?
为什么这么问？
Why ask about him?
这个人有些奇怪
There's something strange about him.
我觉得他值得怀疑
The fact is I suspect him.
他替我工作已有多年
He's been with me for years.
以前是个和尚
He used to be a monk.
和尚？
A monk?
是梵鱼寺的和尚
Yes, for the Fan Yu Temple.
我可’怜他是个废人
I was sorry for him.
所以才收留他
I hired him.
那梵鱼寺在那里？
Where is the Fan Yu Temple?
离这里不远
Quite near here.
传说那里有个死亡塔
There's rumor to be a Tower of Death.
但是一直以来都没有人见过这个塔
But then, no one has ever seen this tower.
为什么？
Why is that?
我听人说在一百年前
Well, people say hundreds of years ago...
有一位弘光大师，把死亡塔建筑在地底下
An abbot called Hung Kuang built the tower
under the ground.
对不起，李先生，请你出去一会儿
Excuse me, mister. Please leave us for a moment.
我有要事跟堡主商量
I have something to discuss with Master.
你是谁？
Hey, who are you?
我的名字叫安琪儿
My name is Angel.
堡主叫我陪陪你
Lewis asked me to come to keep you company.
喝酒吗？
A drink?
谢谢，我不喝酒
No, thanks. Don't touch it.
那要不要其他东西？
Something else?
我想休息
A rest. I'm tired.
想杀我？
Want to kill me?
快来人呀，堡主被杀死了
Everyone, quick! Master's been murdered!
他替我工作已有多年
He's been with me for years.
以前是个和尚
He was a monk before then.
和尚？
A monk?
是梵鱼寺的和尚
Yes, in the Fan Yu Temple
我可＇怜他是个废人，所以才收留他
Felt sorry for him. I hired him.
我听人说在一百年前
People say that hundreds of years ago...
有一位弘光大师，把死亡塔建筑在地底下
an abbot called Hung Kuang
built the tower of death. under the ground.
堡主叫我陪陪你
Lewis asked me to keep you company.
想杀我？
Do you want to kill me?
你为什么要杀堡主?
Why did you kill Lewis?
这对你有什么好处？假冒为善的人
What do you gain by it?
Funny way of being grateful!
你也把秦谷杀了，还嫁祸给堡主
You killed Chin Ku, didn't you...
but you tried to frame Lewis.
究竟你有什么阴谋？
What do you achieve by doing that?
行刺我的也是你，对吗？
And you're the one who attacked me, aren't you?
死亡塔在那儿？
Where is the Tower of Death?
不要装傻
Don't try to play dumb with me.
别说我欺负你这个残废
I'll take a handicap.
让你一只手
Just one hand.
再公平一点，让你两只手
Even fairer, no hands.
死亡塔在那儿？带我去
Now where's the Tower of Death? Take me there.
快说
Better speak up.
别再耍把戏
I'm tired of playing games with you.
说，要不然我就杀了你
Start talking or I'll tear you apart.
死亡塔在那里？
Now where's the tower?
去死吧
You can go to hell!
我可不怕你
Cause I'm not afraid of you.
我这只手会对你不利
I hate to tell you that hand will do you no good.
你是谁？
Hey, who are you?
我？
Me?
小偷
Jack the Ripper.
你还生存？
You're still alive.
当然，有谁能杀得了我？
Of course, I'm alive. No one can defeat me.
你装死究竟是为什么？
But why did you pretend to be dead?
你问得太多问题了
You're asking too many questions.
看在你是李振强的弟弟份上
I'll let you go since you're Billy Lo's brother.
马上滚
Get out while you can.
这是你最后的机会
It's your last chance.
没查出真相之前，我决不会离开
I'm not leaving here till I know the truth!
李振国，你最好别再多管闲事
Bobby Lo, you'd better stay out of this.
在我改变主意之前滚
Now get out before I change my mind.
我哥哥是为了你而死
My brother died for you.
他为了保护你的棺材但你却杀害他？
He tried to prevent someone from stealing
your coffin, and you had him killed!
你说的不是真的
You're nowhere near to the truth, kid.
我和他的死根本没有关系
I had nothing to do with his death.
我是他的好朋友，为什么要杀他？
He was my good friend. Why should I kill him?
对不起，这是他自己找来的
I'm sorry. He brought it on himself.
我是个功夫专家
I might be a kung fu expert
但我也需要钱呀
but I need cash.
毒品生意可以帮我赚到钱
Drug trafficking was my answer.
我可以永远过着奢华的生活
Now I can live in luxury forever.
原来你一直是干这卑鄙的事
So you've been in this drug business
for some time.
是呀
That's correct, my boy.
我想尽办汰，才有今天这个地位
I really had to work hard to get where I am.
再说，毒品这门生意竞争那么激烈
You see there's a lot of competition.
我怎会让任何事阻碍我
That's why I won't let anything stand in my way.
你最好现在就离开
If you value your life,
you'd better leave right now.
为什么在坟场你又用直升机…
First tell me why you used the chopper...
劫走自己的棺材？
to steal your own coffin.
很多人已知道
Many people know that
我做这门生意
I'm in this business.
我不想国际反毒组再查我，所以扮死
I wanted to shake Interpol off my trail.
但我怕他们开棺验尸，所以派人抢走棺材
I was afraid they'd check the coffin.
现在棺材没有了，他们就没证据
Now, they have no evidence.
你别以为这样就没事
You won't get away with this!
因为我要为我哥哥报仇
Cause I intend to take revenge for my brother!
报仇
Take revenge.
只怕你做不到
You're not good enough.
你永远也不会打败我
You'll never defeat me.
我就送你上西天，让你们两人见见面
And now I'll be more than happy to let you
join your brother.
这是你自己找死
You've asked for it, kid.
你这种玩意能吓唬了我吗？
It takes more than that to fight me.
秦谷的绝招
Chin Ku's deadly sword.
我要用振强的截拳道
I'll have to use Billy's Jeet Kune Do style.